All right! I haven't been
on a mission in ages!
（ナルト）よっしゃ！
チョー久々の任務だってばよ！
（サクラ）ナルト　うるさい！
Pipe down, Naruto!
（綱手）あまり
喜べる事案でもないがな。
It's not something
to rejoice over.
え？
Huh?
火の国と国境を接する→
There's been an incident
in the small village
小国の小さい村で　事件があった。
of a small nation bordering
the Land of Fire.
そこの住人が皆殺しに
されたそうだ。
The inhabitants there
were slaughtered.
マジ！？
– Huh?!
– Are you serious?!
（綱手）そこは　昔から→
Since days long past,
神聖域扱いをされていた場所で→
that location has been a site
reserved for sacred use.
ホールと呼ばれていた。
And it's been referred to
as "The Hole."
秘法が隠されているという
噂もあって→
There were rumors of it
having hidden treasure
それを狙う盗賊らから→
and it seems there were
defense measures in place
防人が防衛に
当たっていたようだが。
to guard the area from bandits.
（サクラ）それにしても全滅だなんて。
But total annihilation?
できれば　もっと人手を
増やしたいところだが→
I wish I could assign you
more people,
but we have serious issues
to deal with in our village too.
里も今　いろいろと
面倒が重なってな。
（ヤマト）先日の里の外の仮設墓地が
荒らされた件ですか？
Are you referring to
the grave-robbing incident
at the cemetery outside the village?
（綱手）うむ。　それと　暁のメンバーを
封印している森での…。
Yes.
Also the attack in the forest where
the Akatsuki is sealed away…
（サイ）件の鎌の盗難ですね。
Where the sickle was stolen?
我々も
これから何かと忙しい時期だが→
Things will become much
more hectic for us,
一般の人々の不幸を→
but we cannot ignore anything
inflicted upon the general public.
ないがしろにするわけには
いかない。
村を襲った犯人を突き止め→
Apprehend the ones responsible
for attacking the village,
しかるべき制裁を与える。
頼んだぞ。
and punish them.
I'm counting on you.
（３人）はい。
おう！
– Yes, ma'am!
All right!
（ヤマト）ほとんど焼け落ちている。
Everything's burned to the ground…
村を襲った連中は
何の武器を使ったんだ？
What kind of weapons
did the assailants use?
すごい木の群生ね。
What an amazing forest!
ここの外は　草ひとつ生えていない
荒野なのに。
But just a bit beyond this
is barren land…
（サイ）宝物庫ですかね？
Could this be
a treasure storehouse?
確認してみよう。
Let's find out.
Oh…
この泉の水を
どこかに送っているのね。
Spring water is being
pumped somewhere.
地下に　こんな空間が…。
A space like this…
exists underground?
広い。
不思議な部屋だ。
It's huge.
What a strange room…
何もない。
There's nothing in here.
盗まれたのかな。
そのようだな。
Could it have been robbers?
Looks that way…
（シセル）動くな！
Don't move!
事に乗じて盗みを企んだか。
Are you trying to exploit
the current situation and rob us?
違う。
我々は　国の依頼で動いている→
No. We're here on request
by your government.
木ノ葉隠れの忍だ。
We are Hidden Leaf shinobi.
この村の調査に来たんだ。
We are here to investigate.
失礼しました。
お話はうかがっております。
I beg your pardon.
We are aware of that request.
あなた方は？
And who are you?
近隣のハチョウ町を守る
警備隊のものです。
We are a security unit from
the neighboring town of Hachou.
トニカ村とは　友好関係にありました。
Tonika Village and our town
have a pact of friendship.
なるほど。
I see.
どうぞ　こちらへ。
会っていただきたい方がいます。
Please come this way.
There is someone
I'd like you to meet.
（ディソナス）シセル。
Shiseru…
その方々は？
Who are they?
そうでしたか。
すばやい対応に感謝します。
I see.
I appreciate your quick response.
私は　ディソナス。
ハチョウ町の町長をしております。
I am Disonasu,
the head of Hachou Village.
先日
幸いにも難を逃れた村の方が→
Yesterday, a few who
escaped death
町に助けを求めてきて→
came to the village seeking help,
and the situation came to light.
それで今回の事態が
発覚したのです。
（ヤマト）襲撃犯に心当たりなどは？
Do you have any idea
who the assailants were?
（ディソナス）いいえ。
No…
I believe bandits have attacked
on a number of occasions,
宝のウワサを聞きつけた盗賊たちが→
村の防人と争うことは
幾度もあったようですが。
lured by rumors of treasure.
その宝ですが　どのようなものか
ご存じでしたか？
This treasure? Do you know
what it's supposed to be?
いえ。
No… I think only a few
in the village knew.
おそらく　村でも知っていたのは
ごく一部かと。
（サクラ）つまり　誰かが何かに
襲われたってことかな。
So I guess someone
was attacked by something…
Man, this water tastes great!
チョーうめえってばよ　この水！
アンタねぇ…。
Oh, you…
でも　ホントきれい。
It is pretty though…
まるで　このホールの中だけ→
Inside this "Hole"…
あたりの生気や営みを
吸い取って→
It's like it sucked up the life and
energy of everything around it…
繁栄を謳歌しているみたい。
It's just exploding with vitality.
そのとおり。
You are absolutely right…
ここの水は　命に満ち溢れている。
This water overflows with life.
いつの間に！
When did you appear?
久しぶりだね　２人とも。
It's been a long time, you two.
（カブト）フフフフ…。
カブト！
Kabuto!
Why you…!
フフフ…。
とりゃ～！
相変わらずケンカ腰だね　キミは。
As always, you love getting
into fights, don't you?
何やってんのよ　こんなとこで。
What are you doing here?
まあ　いろいろとね。
Oh, this and that…
今は　ちょっとした研究さ。
Right now…
I'm conducting some research.
なんだってばよ　それは…。
What the hell is that?
（カブト）この蛇たちは
大蛇丸様の細胞から→
I created these snakes using
Lord Orochimaru's cells.
僕が作りあげたもの。
強い再生能力のおかげで
あっという間に増殖できる。
Their regenerative power
is so strong.
They can multiply in no time.
そして　僕のすばらしい実験の
成果によって→
And…thanks to the success
of my experiments,
他の生物の細胞核を植えつけ→
I'm able to implant the nucleus
of other living things
遺伝子情報を
再生することができるんだ。
and regenerate genetic data.
都合のいいことに
ここの水はどうやら→
Conveniently, this water seems
to accelerate cell division
細胞分裂を
非常に促進してくれるようだ。
at an extremely high rate.
それこそ　ウイルス並みのね。
It's almost like a virus.
そして　生まれる。
And then…birth…
新しい　命が。
A new…life.
まさか　暁の…。
It can't be, it's the Akatsuki's…
そう　飛段。
Yes… Hidan.
どうやら　この地にいるのは
偶然じゃなさそうだな。
I guess you're not here
by coincidence.
村を襲ったのは　お前か。
Are you the one who attacked
the village?
訳も含めて　他にも　いろいろと
聞かせてもらおうか。
But since you are here,
you can tell us what happened.
捕まえる？　僕を。
You think you can capture me?
逃がしはしない。
We won't let you get away.
どうかな？
I wonder about that.
駒は　これだけじゃない。
This isn't my only pawn.
長門！
Nagato?!
イタチか。
これは　暁のメンバー。
Itachi?!
They're…members of the Akatsuki!
アスマ先生と　ハヤテ先生！
Asuma Sensei and…
Hayate Sensei?!
まさか　穢土転生！？
Not…Reanimation?!
テメエ！
アンタが墓荒らしを！
You bastard!
You robbed their graves!
あれは…。
That's…?
SICKLE
フフフ　楽しめそうだ。
I'm going to enjoy this.
Quit…screwing around!
ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
Naruto!
ナルト！
隊長！
Captain!
♪～
（カブト）く…　なぜ動かない？
Why aren't they moving?
Is the jutsu still…
まだ術のスキルが足りてないのか。
not complete?!
あっ！
隊長　ソイツに血をとられないで。
Captain, don't let that guy get
a hold of any of your blood!
I know that!
（ヤマト）わかってる。
♪～
先生　ごめん。
I'm sorry…Sensei!
Shiseru!
シセル。
《クソ　もう息がもたねえ…》
I can't hold my breath any longer…
POWER
Mina, you really like
that melody, don't you?
ミィナは
そのメロディ－が好きなんだね。
自分で作ったのかい？
Did you compose it yourself?
（ミィナ）聞こえるの。
聞こえる？
I hear it.
Hear it?
Hey, you're pretty weird.
（レオ）お前　変だよな！
あ！
あ　これ先生？
似てねえ。
Is this supposed to be Sensei?
That doesn't look like Sensei!
I'm not done yet!
描きかけだもん　返して！
– Give it back.
– Here, here!
ほらほら　とってみな！
お兄ちゃん！
– Come and get it!
– Brother!
– Give it back!
– Here, here!
返して！
レオ。
Leo…
Dokku Sensei, eh?
ドック先生か
元気にしてるかな？
Is he doing well?
Uh-huh.
うん。
もう　こんな！
He's like this.
また太ったか？
He's gotten bigger?
But he's cute as a teddy bear.
でも　クマさんみたいで
かわいい。
Huh?
ええ？
プニプニ！
Nice and soft!
More like big and fat.
ブクブクだろ？
アハハ！
彼が好き？
Do you like him?
Yup!
うん。
好き！
A lot!
そうか。
I see!
アイツも　防人よりは
性に合ってるようじゃな。
It seems he's more suited to
this than being a guard.
家の中へ！　隠れて！
Get inside and hide!
おじいちゃんは　どこ？
Where's Grandpa?
キャー！
う！
うわ～！
うわっ　うわ～！
あ！
ああ！
うわ！
あ～！
え～ん！
No…!
ヤダ　死ぬのヤダ～！
I don't wanna die!
（レオ）助けて　誰か助けて！
Help… Someone, please help!
助けて～！
Help!
ゴホゴホ！
（ドック）レオ　レオ　レオ！
Leo?
Leo! Leo!
ドック先生！
レオ！
Dokku Sensei!
Leo!
先生！
ミィナ！
– Sensei…
– Minna!
飛び降りて　受け止めるから！
Jump! I'll catch you.
さあ　早く！
Come on, hurry!
イヤ！
ミィナ　急がないと！
Don't wanna…
Mina, you have to hurry!
怖い！
I'm scared!
ミィナちゃんは　僕が嫌い？
Don't you like me, Mina?
信用できない？
Can you trust me?
ううん。
Uh-huh.
なら！　勇気を出して！
Then, be brave!
えいっ！
頑張ったね　すごいよ！
You did good!
That was amazing.
Okay, now you, Leo!
さあ　レオ！
ハァ　ハァ…。
行っちゃ　ヤダ。
Don't go…
村には　まだ　助けられる人たちが
いるかもしれない。
There might still be people in
the village that need my help!
ミィナちゃんは　ヨシ君や
サッちゃんに　会いたくないの？
Mina, don't you want to see
Yoshi and Satchi?
いいかい？
Listen to me.
If I don't come back,
you must go to Hachou Town.
もし　僕が戻ってこなかったら
ハチョウ町へ行くんだ。　わかるよね？
Got that?
町に着いたら　役場に行って
助けを求めるんだ。　できるよね？
When you get to town,
go to the town hall and get help.
You can do it, right?
– Uh-huh!
そしたら　そしたら…。
頑張って！
はぁ…。
♪～
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート　名曲！
にっぽんの歌』２時間スペシャル。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の
豪華な歌手の皆さんによる→